Contact

bwrmabus@yahoo.com

www.linkedin.com/in/joseph-albert-villanueva-m-s-r-n-8825247b (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Hospitals
Healthcare Management
Emergency Nursing

Joseph Albert Villanueva M.S., R.N.

Emergency Department at CHI St. Luke's Health Spring, Texas

Summary

Experienced Nurse Manager and operations professional with a demonstrated history of working in the hospital & health care industry for 24 years. Skilled in Emergency Nursing, Emergency Care, Healthcare Management and Patient Safety & Quality. Accomplished in The Joint Commission Accreditation of facilities and processes. Extensive work in the formulation and maintenance of facility policies and procedures. Strong operations professional managing staff of the Emergency Department. Experienced in start-up of four free standing Emergency Departments.

Experience

CHI St. Luke's Health

9 years 7 months

Nurse Manager Emergency Dept.

August 2019 - Present (10 months)

Spring, TX, United States

Springwoods Village, Harmony HOPD & Conroe HOPD

Emergency Department/House Supervisor

November 2010 - August 2019 (8 years 10 months)

Lakeside & Springwoods Village, The Woodlands, Texas

Methodist Health System

Emergency Room RN

August 2009 - October 2012 (3 years 3 months)

Willowbrook, Houston, Texas

Memorial Hermann Health System

Emergency Room RN

August 2006 - November 2010 (4 years 4 months)

The Woodlands. Texas

Clara Maass Medical Center Emergency Room RN/Charge Nurse October 2002 - June 2006 (3 years 9 months)

Belleville, New Jersey

Rivington House HCF
Resident Care Coordinator RN
October 1997 - October 2002 (5 years 1 month)
Manhattan, New York City, New York

St. Vincents Hospital & Medical Center Staff RN October 1996 - October 1997 (1 year 1 month) Manhattan, New York City, New York

Education

Sam Houston State University

Master of Science (MS), Health Care Quality & Safety · (2018 - 2019)

St. Vincent's Hospital School of Nursing Diploma in Nursing · (1994 - 1996)

Ateneo de Manila University Bachelor's Degree, Economics